docno	NN	O
:	:	O
1111Transition	CD	O
services	NNS	O
now	RB	B-DATE
mandatory	VBP	O
for	IN	O
soldiersBy	NN	O
Jim	NNP	B-PERSON
Tice	NNP	I-PERSON
-	:	O
Staff	NN	O
writerPosted	VBN	O
:	:	O
Tuesday	NNP	B-DATE
Apr	NNP	I-DATE
3	CD	I-DATE
,	,	I-DATE
2012	CD	I-DATE
16:44:56	CD	B-TIME
EDTFORT	NNP	O
KNOX	NNP	O
,	,	O
Ky.	NNP	B-STATE_OR_PROVINCE
-	:	O
Soldiers	NNS	O
now	RB	B-DATE
must	MD	O
participate	VB	O
in	IN	O
transition	NN	O
services	NNS	O
before	IN	O
they	PRP	O
leave	VBP	O
active	JJ	O
duty.An	NN	O
execution	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH
order	NN	O
requiring	VBG	O
them	PRP	O
to	TO	O
make	VB	O
use	NN	O
of	IN	O
the	DT	O
services	NNS	O
is	VBZ	O
in	IN	O
force	NN	O
throughout	IN	O
the	DT	O
Army.The	NNP	O
order	NN	O
applies	NNS	O
to	TO	O
all	DT	O
soldiers	NNS	O
who	WP	O
are	VBP	O
leaving	VBG	O
active	JJ	O
duty	NN	O
,	,	O
whether	IN	O
they	PRP	O
are	VBP	O
Regular	JJ	B-ORGANIZATION
Army	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION
members	NNS	O
who	WP	O
are	VBP	O
separating	VBG	O
or	CC	O
retiring	VBG	O
or	CC	O
reservists	NNS	O
demobilizing	VBG	O
after	IN	O
six	CD	B-DURATION
months	NNS	I-DURATION
or	CC	O
more	JJR	O
on	IN	O
active	JJ	O
duty.The	NN	O
order	NN	O
,	,	O
which	WDT	O
implements	VBZ	O
a	DT	O
directive	JJ	O
issued	VBN	O
last	JJ	B-DATE
year	NN	I-DATE
by	IN	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
Secretary	NNP	B-TITLE
John	NNP	B-PERSON
McHugh	NNP	I-PERSON
,	,	O
further	JJ	O
requires	VBZ	O
that	IN	O
transition	NN	O
processing	NN	O
begin	NN	O
at	IN	B-DURATION
least	JJS	I-DURATION
12	CD	I-DURATION
months	NNS	I-DURATION
before	IN	O
a	DT	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE
leaves	VBZ	O
active	JJ	O
duty	NN	O
and	CC	O
that	IN	O
the	DT	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE
's	POS	O
commander	NN	B-TITLE
oversee	VBD	O
the	DT	O
process.The	JJ	O
new	JJ	O
procedures	NNS	O
will	MD	O
be	VB	O
bolstered	VBN	O
later	RBR	B-DATE
this	DT	I-DATE
year	NN	I-DATE
when	WRB	O
the	DT	O
Veterans	NNP	B-MISC
Opportunity	NNP	I-MISC
to	TO	I-MISC
Work	NNP	I-MISC
Act	NNP	I-MISC
is	VBZ	O
implemented	VBN	O
Nov.	NNP	B-DATE
20	CD	I-DATE
for	IN	O
all	PDT	O
the	DT	O
military	JJ	O
services	NNS	O
.	.	O

``	``	O
From	IN	O
the	DT	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
standpoint	NN	O
,	,	O
we	PRP	O
are	VBP	O
planning	VBG	O
for	IN	O
that	DT	O
mandate	NN	O
,	,	O
and	CC	O
getting	VBG	O
additional	JJ	O
resources	NNS	O
to	TO	O
support	VB	O
implementation	NN	O
across	IN	O
the	DT	O
active	JJ	O
and	CC	O
reserve	JJ	O
components	NNS	O
,	,	O
''	''	O
said	VBD	O
Walter	NNP	B-PERSON
M.	NNP	I-PERSON
Herd	NNP	I-PERSON
,	,	O
director	NN	B-TITLE
of	IN	O
the	DT	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
Career	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION
and	CC	O
Alumni	NNP	O
Program.This	NNP	O
will	MD	O
result	VB	O
in	IN	O
about	IN	O
a	DT	O
300	CD	B-PERCENT
percent	NN	I-PERCENT
increase	NN	O
in	IN	O
the	DT	O
number	NN	O
of	IN	O
soldiers	NNS	O
participating	VBG	O
in	IN	O
transition	NN	O
services	NNS	O
,	,	O
Herd	NNP	O
said.ACAP	NN	O
,	,	O
a	DT	O
longtime	JJ	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
program	NN	O
,	,	O
assists	VBZ	O
departing	VBG	O
soldiers	NNS	O
,	,	O
family	NN	O
members	NNS	O
and	CC	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
career	NN	O
civilians	NNS	O
in	IN	O
preparing	VBG	O
for	IN	O
civilian	JJ	O
life	NN	O
through	IN	O
myriad	JJ	O
counseling	NN	O
,	,	O
education	NN	O
,	,	O
job-preparation	NN	O
and	CC	O
job-search	NN	O
services	NNS	O
at	IN	O
54	CD	B-NUMBER
centers	NNS	O
in	IN	O
the	DT	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY
and	CC	O
overseas.The	JJ	O
centers	NNS	O
are	VBP	O
staffed	VBN	O
by	IN	O
counselors	NNS	O
who	WP	O
have	VBP	O
graduate	NN	O
degrees	NNS	O
in	IN	O
counseling	NN	O
and	CC	O
who	WP	O
can	MD	O
link	VB	O
up	RP	O
departing	VBG	O
soldiers	NNS	O
with	IN	O
training	NN	O
and	CC	O
services	NNS	O
offered	VBN	O
by	IN	O
the	DT	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
and	CC	O
other	JJ	O
government	NN	O
agencies	NNS	O
,	,	O
such	JJ	O
as	IN	O
the	DT	O
Labor	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
and	CC	O
Veterans	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION
Affairs	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION
departments.ACAP	NN	I-ORGANIZATION
also	RB	O
operates	VBZ	O
a	DT	O
new	JJ	O
24-hour	JJ	B-DURATION
,	,	O
seven-day-a-week	JJ	B-DURATION
call	NN	O
center	NN	O
here	RB	O
,	,	O
and	CC	O
an	DT	O
interactive	JJ	O
website	NN	O
for	IN	O
the	DT	O
virtual	JJ	O
delivery	NN	O
of	IN	O
information	NN	O
and	CC	O
services	NNS	O
,	,	O
to	TO	O
include	VB	O
counseling.Regular	JJ	B-ORGANIZATION
Army	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION
soldiers	NNS	O
leaving	VBG	O
active	JJ	O
duty	NN	O
should	MD	O
begin	VB	O
their	PRP$	O
transition	NN	O
24	CD	B-DURATION
months	NNS	I-DURATION
in	IN	O
advance	NN	O
of	IN	O
retirement	NN	O
and	CC	O
18	CD	B-DURATION
to	TO	I-DURATION
12	CD	I-DURATION
months	NNS	I-DURATION
in	IN	O
advance	NN	O
of	IN	O
separation	NN	O
,	,	O
Herd	NNP	B-PERSON
said	VBD	O
.	.	O

