docno	NN	O	0	ROOT
:	:	O	1	punct
1111Transition	CD	O	4	compound
services	NNS	O	1	dep
now	RB	B-DATE	6	advmod
mandatory	VBP	O	4	amod
for	IN	O	10	case
soldiersBy	NN	O	10	compound
Jim	NNP	B-PERSON	10	compound
Tice	NNP	I-PERSON	6	nmod
-	:	O	10	punct
Staff	NN	O	13	compound
writerPosted	VBN	O	10	dep
:	:	O	4	punct
Tuesday	NNP	B-DATE	16	compound
Apr	NNP	I-DATE	29	nsubj
3	CD	I-DATE	16	nummod
,	,	I-DATE	16	punct
2012	CD	I-DATE	20	compound
16:44:56	CD	B-TIME	16	nummod
EDTFORT	NNP	O	22	compound
KNOX	NNP	O	16	dep
,	,	O	22	punct
Ky.	NNP	B-STATE_OR_PROVINCE	22	appos
-	:	O	16	punct
Soldiers	NNS	O	16	dep
now	RB	B-DATE	29	advmod
must	MD	O	29	aux
participate	VB	O	4	dep
in	IN	O	32	case
transition	NN	O	32	compound
services	NNS	O	29	nmod
before	IN	O	35	mark
they	PRP	O	35	nsubj
leave	VBP	O	29	advcl
active	JJ	O	39	amod
duty.An	NN	O	39	amod
execution	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	39	compound
order	NN	O	35	dobj
requiring	VBG	O	39	acl
them	PRP	O	40	dobj
to	TO	O	43	mark
make	VB	O	40	xcomp
use	NN	O	43	dobj
of	IN	O	47	case
the	DT	O	47	det
services	NNS	O	44	nmod
is	VBZ	O	50	cop
in	IN	O	50	case
force	NN	O	29	advcl
throughout	IN	O	54	case
the	DT	O	54	det
Army.The	NNP	O	54	compound
order	NN	O	50	nmod
applies	NNS	O	50	acl
to	TO	O	58	case
all	DT	O	58	det
soldiers	NNS	O	55	nmod
who	WP	O	61	nsubj
are	VBP	O	61	aux
leaving	VBG	O	58	acl:relcl
active	JJ	O	63	amod
duty	NN	O	61	dobj
,	,	O	50	punct
whether	IN	O	70	mark
they	PRP	O	70	nsubj
are	VBP	O	70	cop
Regular	JJ	B-ORGANIZATION	70	amod
Army	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	70	compound
members	NNS	O	50	dep
who	WP	O	73	nsubj
are	VBP	O	73	aux
separating	VBG	O	70	acl:relcl
or	CC	O	73	cc
retiring	VBG	O	73	conj
or	CC	O	73	cc
reservists	NNS	O	78	nsubj
demobilizing	VBG	O	73	conj
after	IN	O	81	case
six	CD	B-DURATION	81	nummod
months	NNS	I-DURATION	78	nmod
or	CC	O	83	cc
more	JJR	O	81	nummod
on	IN	O	87	case
active	JJ	O	87	amod
duty.The	NN	O	87	compound
order	NN	O	78	nmod
,	,	O	87	punct
which	WDT	O	90	nsubj
implements	VBZ	O	87	acl:relcl
a	DT	O	92	det
directive	JJ	O	90	dobj
issued	VBN	O	92	acl
last	JJ	B-DATE	95	amod
year	NN	I-DATE	93	nmod:tmod
by	IN	O	100	case
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	100	compound
Secretary	NNP	B-TITLE	100	compound
John	NNP	B-PERSON	100	compound
McHugh	NNP	I-PERSON	93	nmod
,	,	O	70	punct
further	JJ	O	103	advmod
requires	VBZ	O	70	dep
that	IN	O	107	mark
transition	NN	O	106	compound
processing	NN	O	107	nsubj
begin	NN	O	103	ccomp
at	IN	B-DURATION	109	case
least	JJS	I-DURATION	110	nmod:npmod
12	CD	I-DURATION	111	nummod
months	NNS	I-DURATION	107	nmod:tmod
before	IN	O	115	mark
a	DT	O	114	det
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	115	nsubj
leaves	VBZ	O	107	advcl
active	JJ	O	117	amod
duty	NN	O	115	dobj
and	CC	O	107	cc
that	IN	O	124	mark
the	DT	O	121	det
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	123	nmod:poss
's	POS	O	121	case
commander	NN	B-TITLE	124	nsubj
oversee	VBD	O	107	conj
the	DT	O	128	det
process.The	JJ	O	128	compound
new	JJ	O	128	amod
procedures	NNS	O	131	nsubjpass
will	MD	O	131	aux
be	VB	O	131	auxpass
bolstered	VBN	O	124	ccomp
later	RBR	B-DATE	134	advmod
this	DT	I-DATE	134	det
year	NN	I-DATE	131	nmod:tmod
when	WRB	O	143	advmod
the	DT	O	138	det
Veterans	NNP	B-MISC	138	compound
Opportunity	NNP	I-MISC	143	nsubjpass
to	TO	I-MISC	141	case
Work	NNP	I-MISC	141	compound
Act	NNP	I-MISC	138	nmod
is	VBZ	O	143	auxpass
implemented	VBN	O	131	advcl
Nov.	NNP	B-DATE	143	nmod:tmod
20	CD	I-DATE	144	nummod
for	IN	O	150	case
all	PDT	O	150	det:predet
the	DT	O	150	det
military	JJ	O	150	amod
services	NNS	O	143	nmod
.	.	O	1	punct

